Guide to the Basil Rauch, collector, Vietnam documentation, 1942-1980
Rauch, Basil (collector) Vietnam documentation, 1942-1980
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Basil Rauch, collector, Vietnam documentation, 1942-1980.
4381
Basil Rauch, 1908-
2 cubic ft.
Documents.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Documents pertaining to the origins of the conflict in Indochina after World War II.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Historian.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Documents pertaining to the origins of the conflict in Indochina after World War II.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rauch, Basil, 1908-
Subjects:
Indochinese War, 1946-1954.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.
Places:
United States--Foreign relations--Indochina.; Great Britain--Foreign relations--Indochina.; France--Foreign relations--Indochina.; Vietnam--Politics and government--1945-1975.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- C. de V. & Churchill Coll., 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Card notes on Indochina, apparently from Churchill College Library and the Chateau de Vincennes
- DDE, 1953- (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Dwight D. Eisenhower Library
- PRO - Bib. Nle. - Nanterre (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  Public Records Office (Kew, England) Bibliograpical Notes. Spiral notebook, with handwritten bibliographical notations (1944-1945) from Prime Minister's Office, with concise extracts (ca. 40 pp.). Also, ca. 68 pp. of bibliographical notes and books from the Library at Nanterre
- PRO - PREM 314 + FO, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  Classified documents on French Indo-China from Public Records Office (Foreign Office documents)
- Mary Speers' Notes, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Foreign Office series 371/35921, ff. Mostly on wartime relations with France.
- My Notes 1980 - PRO & Rhodes House (Box 1, Folder 8)
  CAB 121/741 - Notes taken on memos on Indochina for PM from Foreign Section. File: "My Notes 1980: PRO & Roosevelt." CAB 120/56 - 121/741. Succinct notes of heart of documents re: French Indochina (ca. 40-50 pp.). Notebook cover headed "Cabinet Officers etc." has several pages of references to A. Creech Jones.
  2nd notebook: Rhodes Library Oxford - About 100 pp. of penciled notes on FO 371; CO 824 Register; CO 872-4-9 inclusive (1942, 1942) Mostly to FO 371/371779-90
- DDE '54 - documents, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- National Archives - Use of Indo China Resistance Forces, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- National Archives, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Declassified documents on Indochina
- National Archives, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- National Archives, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- National Archives Jan.-Aug., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- National Archives Sept.-Dec., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- National Archives - to Apr. 12, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- National Archives Apr.-June, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- National Archives July-Dec., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- National Archives, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- National Archives, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
- National Archives, 1940-1946 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Roosevelt Library, 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Truman Library (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Truman Library, 1945-1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- DDE, 1954-1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- DDE Lib. Declass. '77, 1953-1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- DDE - NSC (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Dulles Papers, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  From Princeton University Library. Includes notes, 1976-1977